Hello! I'm Nestor Sanchez!

PYTHON DEVELOPER || WWW.NESTORSAN.COM

41, JOAN FUSTER, VILANOVA I LA GELTRÚ (BARCELONA), SPAIN

PHONE: +34 652 88 74 16 || EMAIL: hi@nestorsan.com || SKYPE: editor.nestor

SOCIAL LINKS: LINKEDIN || GITHUB || HACKERRANK || STACKOVERFLOW



WHO I AM IN 706 CHARACTERS ||

In a nutshell, I'm a scientist-type personality who studied cinema and TV, but focused on making my career in the mobile marketing industry founding two content brands from scratch.

Over the years, I created a portfolio with more than 500 adult videos, 300 android games and utilities and 200 HTML5 games. In addition, I secured distribution agreements in more than 50 countries, reaching millions of consumers through mobile operators' portals.

After managing my own company for more than 5 years, I found my passion and vocation in Python programming, and I'd like to follow this path. I'm looking for a place where I can contribute to build a better world, programmatically. Therefore, I need a team to work with and a mission to fulfill, and this is the reason I do my first CV in ten years.

|| KEY SKILLS ||

- Python programming
- Databases: MySQL / PostgreSQL
- Frameworks: Django Web Framework & Flask "Micro" Web Framework
- REST API's: Django Rest Framework, Fastapi,
- Dev. Tools: Docker, Travis CI, Git / Github.
- Write unit tests, test-driven development & style guide enforcement with Flake8.
- Statistics & Data: Numpy, Pandas, Scrapy.
- Machine Learning / Al: Scikit Learn

| PYTHON PROJECTS ||

- <u>Email Magnet</u>: command line app to search for valid emails of corporate employers.
- Email Magnet with Django: same as above, but to be deployed as a web app and with more feature such as user authentification and export data in CSV.
- Inmogadget: a calculator for Real State
 Agents that simplify difficult calculations
 such as taxes, commissions, expenses and
 sell prices of real state operations.
- <u>Cooperation Fit</u>: a production ready REST API to create a cooperative marketplace that links NGO's with digital cooperators.
- Rest API's: <u>Recipes API</u>, <u>Quora Clon API</u>

WHAT THE HECK SET ME APART FROM THE REST?

- - - Self-thaught developer & fast learner - - -

- - - Former CEO: able to translate complex business ideas into a roadmap with actionable steps - - -

- - - Background in Arts, Tech and Economics - - -

--- 5 years dealing with remote dev teams management ---

- - - Happily served Top World Brands such as: - - -

















QUALIFICATIONS

DEGREE IN AUDIOVISUAL COMMUNICATION

UNIVERSITAT POMPEU FABRA, BARCELONA, 2006-2011

Modules covered include Cinema, TV, radio, 3D animation and Web Development. Specialized in script writing for Cinema.

WORK EXPERIENCE ||

GENERAL MANAGER & DEVELOPER

XEMOB LABS S.L., VILANOVA I LA G. BARECLONA

JUN 2016 - PRESENT

Xemob Labs is a small company focusing on the development and distribution of android and HTML5 products for mobile operators and media companies. As a solopreneur, I wear so many hats. Xemob Labs don't have employers, but I contract freelancers based on each project needs and I manage all the projects from its conception until its deployment. To know more about Xemob, please, visit <u>its website</u>.

FEATURED PROJECT: HTML5 GAMES PLATFORM

I personally developed a white label platform to create game portals like this <u>one</u> with PHP and WordPres. Client's version are live in <u>NZ</u> and <u>UK</u>. For more info, see the <u>brochure</u>.

HIGHLIGHT: ANDROID DEVELOPMENT

I managed and contributed to the development of 23 android apps and the reskin or customization of more than 200 android apps and games.

Catalogue Links: <u>Android Games</u> - <u>Android Apps</u>

GENERAL MANAGER & VIDEO PRODUCER

THE GLAMOURIST CLUB (FORMERLY "BROADCASTING TEAM"), VILANOVA I LA G. BARECLONA : JUL 2015 - DEC 2017

I created a collection of soft adult content specially tailored for mobile operator's market and regulations. I was in charge of source RAW content, edit it to adapt to different markets and distribute it digitally. To know more about this project, please, visit this <u>website</u>.

VIDEO PRODUCTION & TECHNICAL MANAGER

CHERRY MEDIA, VILANOVA I LA G. BARECLONA

DEC 2010 - JUN 2015

Entering this company as an Intern, I end up managing up to 7 employers and being the biggest responsible person in charge of the product of <u>Cherry Media</u>, a Multi-Award Winning Glamour & Lifestyle Video Specialist. Some of my responsibilities are managing the portfolio of Cherry Media, meet new client enquires, manage the production team to do new creative packs of content, do marketing analysis and create promo materials for the company.

MY DEVELOPMENT PATH ||

I'm a self-taught developer. Because of my business needs, I learned to code websites 14 years ago. Then, 5 years ago I learned the basics of Android Development reskining apps and 3 years ago I learned PHP to manage app backends at Xemob.

Finally, 1,5 years ago I fell in love with python. Since then, I can't stop learning and coding.

Some of the courses I followed:

- <u>Codecademy</u>: Data Science Path including Python, Data analysis, Pandas, Numpy, SQL and Machine Learning with scikit-learn.
- Udemy: The complete Guide to Django REST Framework and Vue.js, Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django (Advanced), Modern Web Scraping with Python using Scrapy and Splash & Django 3 Full Stack Websites.

Nowadays, I'm able to deploy my own Python apps in a VPS using django, flask, Docker, TravisCl, gunicorn & Nginx.

I think I'm ready to help business to make better decisions and improve their workflows thanks to technology and data and I'm open for interviews and tests on these topics.

Feel free to write me an email to hi@nestorsan.com with any offer or requirement.